Inventory of the Powell Family Papers 1775-1927
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers of the Powell Family, 1785-1927, n.d. (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Papers, 1860-1869. (Box 2-3)
    - Papers, 1862., 63 items. (Box-folder 3:1-3)
      - Hattie L. Powell, Rome, [?], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 27 October 1862., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:2)
        Comments on incidents of typhoid fever; family news; discusses her minister and baptism of a baby.
      - M[ary] C[ustis] Lee, Richmond, [Virginia], to Selina [(Loyd) Powell], n.p., 30 October 1862., 4 pages. ALS. Including Xcy of ALS (same). 4 pages. (Box-folder 3:2)
        Describes circumstances of her daughter Annie's sickness and death; offers sympathy for death of Charles L. Powell, Jr.; family news; including recital of Fenella's funeral rites; "Earth to Earth, Dust to Dust...".
      - S[arah] J[ane (Powell)] Conrad, Winchester, [Virginia], to "Cousin" Charles L. Powell, "Kenmuir", Trevillion's depot, Louisa County, Virginia, 31 [October] [1862]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:2)
        Discusses business matters in Winchester that she is taking care of for Charles L. Powell; discusses the ear and the situation in Winchester; sends him some books, stating that the Yankees carried off the rest of them; reports of a proposed armistice.
      - "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], "Kenmuir", [Louisa County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 4 November 1862., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Describes sickness causing a delirious state for a few days; family news; knitting as a popular pastime; discusses weather; Yankees still have Gloucester Point as a fort; soldiers suffering from "rot" that kills them.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.],"Kenmuir", [Louisa County, Virginia], to "darling," [one of his daughters, Hattie or Rebecca Powell], n.p., 5 November [18]62., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Discusses [John] Milton's works; family news; Longstreet's Corps has occupied many points near Culpeper Court House.
        Including ANS from Nina Powell, Kenmuir, [Louisa County, Virginia] to "sister," [either Hattie or Rebecca Powell], n.p., 5 November [18]62, reporting family news. 1 page.
        Also including ANS from S[elina] P[owell], Kenmuir, [Louisa County, Virginia]. Expresses grief over Annie Lee's death; asks about Robert E. Lee; prevalence of typhoid fever; describes weather and landscape; Yankees did not disturb Charles L. Powell, Jr.'s grave; family news. 2 pages. ALS.
      - "Friend" Getty McGuire, "Home" [Winchester, Virginia], to Hattie [Powell], n.p., 12 November 1862., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Sends this letter with a letter from Hunter, her brother; comments that Hattie has now been gone from Winchester eight months; says life ins find when Confederate soldiers are in Winchester, but that it is miserable when the Yankees come; says General Jackson has visited them and has his headquarters on the road to Front Royal; says he gave her his photograph and se will send a copy; writes that they are working very hard because the few servants in town are cooking for the soldiers; lists people who will leave town if the Yankees return; says Cousin Betty look unwell because she works so hard in the hospitals; writes that they only have 500 sick beds in the hospitals; mentions the destruction by Yankees in other counties; fears they will soon suffer.
      - Hunter [Getty] McGuire, Camp, H[ea]d Q[uarte]rs, Virginia D[istric]t, to "Friend" [Hattie Powell], n.p., 12 November 1862., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Sends thanks for present he received because [it] will be useful during the winter; expresses desire for peace in the country.
      - Hattie L. Powell, Rome, [?], to "Father," [Charles L. Powell, Sr.], n.p., 16 November 1862., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Much family news; expresses concern that the southern army is suffering from a lack of clothes and the elements.
      - Rebecca Powell, "Springfield", Virginia, to "Mother" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], n.p., 16 November [1862]., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Expresses her feelings of loneliness, as she lives among strangers; expresses other worries of disease and of the war; discusses problems with diphtheria in the neighborhood; comments on the shortage of men in the neighborhood, in particular healthy, attractive ones; discusses the hardships of Uncle Prosser and Aunt [Re]Bec[ca] whose former servants burnt much of their property; news of friends and family.
      - S[arah] J[ane (Powell)] C[onrad],[Winchester, Virginia] to "cousin" [Charles L. Powell, Sr.], ["Kenmuir", Louisa County, Virginia], 22 November [1862]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Discusses the condition of Charles L. Powell's estate and what business has been transacted; lists what articles from their home have been sold, commenting that most people in Winchester are not buying things because they are leaving to journey "up the Valley"; reports that 4000 men are guarding Winchester, that some tobacco has been burned, and that preparation for evacuation is underway; describes Yankee attacks in Charlestown; comments on the effect of the fear of attack on everyone in the town; gives news of friends.
      - "Grandmother" [Catharine Powell], "locust Hill [sic]", [Loudoun County, Virginia], to "granddaughter" [Nina, Rebecca or Hattie Powell], n.p., 2 December [18]62., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Comments on problems with influenza; refers to a Capt. Duff and his defense of Leesburg, [Virginia]; gives news of town since troops have arrived; family news.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.],"Kenmuir", [Louisa County, Virginia], to "darling," [Nina Powell], n.p., 12 December [18]62., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Makes references to the Clarke Cav[al]ry and a Capt. Carter; possessions have been pillaged and towns have been ruined; has to quit farming because of war.
      - S[elina] P[owell],"Kenmuir", [Louisa County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 12 December 1862., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Wishes Nina a Happy Birthday; refers to God and task to enter his Kingdom; mentions a friend who died from diphtheria; discusses [Stonewall] Jackson's opposition to the "enemy" [Yankees] at Port Royal, [Virginia]; family news.
      - Rebecca Powell, "Springfield", Virginia, to "Mother," Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Kenmuir?, 15 December [18]62., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Discusses everyone's fear of diphtheria; much family news.
      - H[attie] L. Powell, Rome, [?], to "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, "Kenmuir", Louisa County, Virginia], 16 December 1862., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Makes references to Gen. [Robert E.] Lee's victories; much family news.
      - Kate Gordon, "Kenmuir", [Louisa County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 17 December [18]62., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Expresses the difficulty of losing so many brave men in the [Civil] war.
      - Hattie L. Powell, Rome, [?] to "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, "Kenmuir", Louisa County, Virginia], 19 December 1862., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Reminisces about their last Christmas together; discusses the servants and their ability to be dangerous.
      - Hattie L. Powell, Rome, [?], to "Father," [Charles L. Powell, Sr., "Kenmuir", Louisa County, Virginia], 21 December 1862., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        Expresses desire for peace and to return to Winchester, [Virginia]; much town and family news; sorry they can't spend Christmas together.
      - H[attie] L. P[owell], Rome, [?], to "Sister," [Rebecca Powell], n.p., 24 December 1862., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
        She has been ill with a cough and cold; family news.
    - Papers, 1863., 57 items. (Box-folder 3:4-5)
      - S[elina] (Lloyd) Powell,"Kenmuir", [Louisa County, Virginia], to daughter," [Nina Powell], Pr[ince] Ed[war]d [County, Virginia], 2 January 1863., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Inquires about a John Tabb; tells activities of Kate [Gordon] who is staying with them; mentions a bombazine [fine twilled silk fabric]; people looking for teaching positions; family news.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, Springfield, [Virginia], to "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, "Kenmuir", Louisa County, Virginia], 2 January 1863., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Much town and family news.
      - Rebecca Powell, Springfield, [Virginia], to "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, "Kenmuir", Louisa County, Virginia], 12 January [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Problems with smallpox; much family news; mentions Judge Lee's[?] suicide.
      - [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], "Kenmuir", [Louisa County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 16 January 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Her husband, Charles L. Powell, Sr., is still looking for a teaching job; recommends reading as a worthwhile hobby.
      - Agnes [Lee], Hickory Hill, [?], to Hattie [Powell], n.p., January [1863?]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Describes how her family spent Christmas; thanks her for the cap she made for her brother Rob; discusses the sadness of Hattie's Christmas; discusses friendship; reports that she heard from Mary[?] who is living behind Yankee lines in King George.
      - Rebecca Powell, Springfield, [Virginia], to "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, "Kenmuir", Louisa County, Virginia], 2 February [18]63., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Mentions a Col. Tucker[?]; talks about her personal health; refers to the "conscript act"; gives impressions of deaths resulting from the [Civil] War and ideas of a forthcoming peace; family news.
      - C. Powell Grady, H[ea]d Q[ua]r[ter]s, Valley District, New Market, Virginia, to "Cousin Nina" [Powell], n.p., 7 February 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Family news; refers to robbery of all servants; tells stories of confrontations with the enemy and experiences while at war; discusses food he has to eat; mentions has heard news of Grandma's death; mentions William Edmonson Jones.
      - Rebecca Powell, Springfield, [Virginia], to "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], n.p., 17 February [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Much family news; discusses her pay for tutorial services.
      - Rebecca [Powell], n.p., to Nina [Powell], n.p., 1 March [1863]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Mentions their father's new employment in Greenville; news of family and friends.
      - "Lou," [Brooker?], n.p. to Nina Powell, n.p., 13 March 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Family news; describes some of daily activities.
        Including ANS from N. C. E.[?], n.p., to Nina Powell, n.p., post 13 March 1863, giving neighborhood news.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, Springfield, [Virginia], to "Mother," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], n.p., 22 March 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Comments on Cavalry's victory in Culpepper [sic], [Virginia]; describes poverty situation in Winchester, [Virginia], as result of [Civil] War; discusses situations in Romney, West Virginia; much family news.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Powhatan County, [Virginia], to "darling," [one of his daughters - Hattie, Rebecca, or Nina Powell], n.p., 1 April [18]63., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Found a teaching job in Powhatan; describes location and plans to build a house.
      - W[illie] J. [?] Hull,"Camp Washington," H[ea]d Q[ua]r[ter]s, N. W. Virginia Brigade, to "Cousin Hattie" [Powell],[Rome], 6 April [18]63., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Comments on his activities in the Army; refers to "the Picketts"; tells of damage and destruction in Winchester, [Virginia], as a result of Yankee invasion.
      - [C.] Powell Grady, H[ea]d Q[ua]r[ter]s, V[irginia] D[istrict], to "dear cousin" [either Hattie, Rebecca, or Nina Powell], n.p., 10 April 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Comments on experiences in Army; expresses sadness that young men can't receive education during the war; family news; states that Tip[?] Powell and Frank Grady were captured in Loudoun, [Virginia].
      - Agnes Lee, Richmond, [Virginia], to Hattie [Powell], n.p., 12 April 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Discusses clothes; family news; says they will visit Shirley [Plantation] soon; says Mary[?] must remain within the Yankee lines because the only way to leave is to walk eighteen miles at night, carrying baggage; mentions Robert E. Lee, George Washington, and Custis Lee.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, Springfield, [Virginia], to "Sister" [Hattie Powell], n.p., 24 April [18]63., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Mentions interest in soldiers, especially the South Carolina gentlemen; talks about sources of entertainment; family news.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, Powhatan County, [Virginia], to "daughter" [either Hattie, Rebecca, or Nina Powell], n.p., 26 April [18]63., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Describes his house and surroundings; family news.
      - S[elina] (Lloyd) Powell, Pr[ince] Edw[ar]d [County, Virginia], to "precious Hattie" [Powell], n.p., 29 April 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Mentions "taking bitters (a tea) made of sarsaparilla root" for strength and to purify her blood; expresses hopes for war to soon be over; Yankees now have Fauquier under their control; family news; refers to receiving news through the Enquirer.
      - Rebecca [C. Powell], n.p., to "Mother," [Selina Lloyd Powell], n.p., [?] May [1863]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Discusses when the family members will see each other; gives news of Powell relatives at Locust Hill; says that goods cannot be sent to them from Locust Hill [Leesburg, Virginia] because of a blockade; inquires about the fighting in Fredericksburg.
      - C. Powell Grady, H[ea]d Q[ua]r[ter]s, Jones Cavalry Brigade, near Culpeper Co[urt] Ho[use],[Virginia], to "cousin Nina" [Powell],[Winchester, Virginia], 5 June 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Talks about General Stuart's decision to review his Division; refers to great loss at Battle of Chancellorsville in the death of Gen[era]l ["Stonewall"] Jackson; describes events of war near Rowlesburg, [West Virginia]; comments on his troops various attacks on different Railroads; gives details about other battles.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Prestwood" [sic], [Mecklenburg County, Virginia?], to Nina [Powell],[Winchester, Virginia?], 13 June 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Much family news; comments on how quickly her chickens are dying.
      - "Cousin" Sarah [Jane (Powell) Conrad], Winchester, [Virginia], to "Hattie" [Harriet Powell], n.p., 8 July [18]63., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Discusses fighting [in the Civil War] and loss of servants; family news and sick and wounded from Battle of Gettysburg.
      - Powell[?] [Grady?], n.p., to "cousin", n.p., 18 July [1863]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Comments on war, pestilence and famine; discusses the [Civil] War.
      - H[orace] Stringfellow, Rector, St. Martin's Parish, Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia, to N[ina] L. Powell,[Winchester, Virginia?], 21 July 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        States that Nina Powell has been recommended to him to take care of his children as well as tutoring them; requests response to his offer.
      - [?] L. [?], "White Marsh", [Gloucester County, Virginia], to Hattie [Powell], n.p., 24 July 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Discusses pillaging by the Yankees; comments on men who have given their lives for the southern cause; much family news.
      - H[orace] Stringfellow, Verdon, Hanover County, [Virginia], to Nina L. Powell, [Winchester, Virginia?], 3 August 1863., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Comments on scarcity of various staples; offers her $300 to come and teach his children.
      - Emily [Powell?], Cousin, Richmond, [Virginia], to Hattie [Powell], n.p., 4 August 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Discusses "keeping house" and how much it costs to do so; family news; comments on the Battle of Manassas.
        Including AN from [?], n.p. to Hatty [sic] [Powell], n.p., n.d., discussing delivery of enclosed note to Custis [Lee]. 1 page.
      - H[orace] Stringfellow,[Hanover County, Virginia], to Miss [Nina] Powell,[Winchester, Virginia?], 14 August 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Attempts to appease Nina's apprehensions about coming to Hanover County if the enemy is there; wants her to begin working the first of October.
      - [Charles Leven Powell, Sr.?], to [?], 17 August [18]63., 1 page. N. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:4)
        Offer to substitute himself [for William Henry Fitzhugh Lee as a Northern prisoner of War].
      - Rebecca C. Powell, "Clover Plains," [?], to Nina [Powell],[Winchester, Virginia or Hanover County, Virginia?], 26 September [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Much family news; questions Nina about her "beaux" and his courting ways; discusses education.
      - "Cousin Powell" [C. Powell Grady], H[ea]d Q[ua]r[te]rs, Lomax[?] Brigade, [?], to Nina [Powell],[either Winchester of Hanover County, Virginia], 1 October 1863., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Refers to burning her previous letter in case of a fight whence it could become public; relates news of troops; family news; discusses fight from the Rappahannock to the Rapidan [Rivers].
      - Hattie L. Powell, Prince Edward [County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], Hanover County, Virginia], 3 October 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
      - Lettie[?], "Linden", [Prince Edward County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 12 October 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Much family news; stats that a man named Taylor Johns has fallen in love with Nina Powell; discusses situation at the Stringfellow's, where Nina now lives.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, Albemarle County, [Virginia], to "wife," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], n.p., 21 October [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Discusses in detail his new teaching position; family information.
      - Hattie [Powell], Prince Edward [County], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 22 October 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Gives cotton prices as $3.75 a yard; discusses Battle at Manassas; much family news.
      - "Mother," S[elina] (Lloyd) P[owell], Charlotte [County, Virginia?], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 24 October 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Comments on her husband's new position in Albemarle; much family news; mentions some events in reference to the Civil War.
      - Rebecca [C. Powell], Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Mother [Selina L. Powell], n.p., 26 October [1863]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Says she saw her father [Charles L. Powell, Sr.] on his way to move into Cousin R's[?]; describes her trip to Charlottesville; expresses satisfaction that her mother is able to stay with Uncle Fred and Lute; reports she has eleven scholars.
      - Hattie L. Powell, "Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 7 November 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Family news; discusses her job as a teacher; discusses "preserving with molasses"; expresses anger and confusion about Nina's beaux David [?].
      - [Charles L. Powell, Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to "wife," [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 12 November [18]63., 2 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Discusses his teaching position.
      - [Hattie Powell], Greenwood [Depot?, Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 12 November [18]63., 4 pages. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:5)
      - Lettie[?], Linden, [Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 16 November 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Gives opinion on attitudes of young people; family news; expresses interest in religion.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, Greenwood Depot, [?], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 23 November [1863]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Discusses plans for Christmas, including costs involved and where they can stay; discusses death of [Cousin?] Temple Grady and its effect on other relatives; discusses teaching and their role in the war effort.
      - Nina [Powell], Forest Hill, [Hanover County, Virginia], to Mother [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], n.p., 25 November [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Refers to a battle at Chattanooga, [Tennessee]; and [General] Longstreet; discusses cotton and its discount price of $18 a bale; comments on young gentlemen who have come to visit her; other town and family news.
      - Hunter McGuire, Camp near Orange County, Virginia, to Hattie [Powell],[Albemarle County, Virginia?], 26 November [18]63., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Thanks Hattie for her kind gift of The Bible; gives details of present experience as a soldier in the [Civil] War; expresses sadness for those who died in the battle.
      - Hattie L. Powell, Blenheim, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Forest Hill, Hanover County, Virginia], 29 November 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Mentions a Carrie Hobson's death resulting from a "perforation of the bowels," (typhoid fever); family and town news; mentions Temple Grady's [brother of C. Powell Grady?] death; refers to having some corsets made.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to wife [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Prince Edward County, Virginia?], 2 December [18]63., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
      - Lettie[?], Danville, [Virginia], to Nina [Powell],["Forest Hill", Hanover County, Virginia], 3 December 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Family news; expresses concern about "national affairs"; discusses religious point of view.
      - [Nina Powell], "Forest Hill", [Hanover County, Virginia], to Mother [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], [Prince Edward County, Virginia?], 4 December [18]63., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Much family news; discusses General Bragg and his great ability as a leader.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to wife [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], [Prince Edward County, Virginia?], 5 December [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Much family news; states that he met Mr. Seddon, Secretary of War and they discussed [Judah] Benjamin; gives some views of what is happening with the [Civil] War.
      - S[elina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to [Nina Powell, "Forest Hill", Hanover County, Virginia], 8 December 1863., 10 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Mentions [General] Longstreet's retreat from Knoxville, [Tennessee]; comments on giving Nina some linen for "sleeves or sleeve bands", family news; discusses harvesting of crops; comments on threats that "Yanks" are making.
      - Cousin Emily [Powell?], Richmond, [Virginia], to Nina [Powell],["Forest Hill", Hanover County, Virginia]. 11 December 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Discusses insufficiency of cotton crops; mentions that her son is on a war vessel, in the ocean, "larger than the Florida and the Alabama."
      - H[attie] L. P[owell], Blenheim, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],["Forest Hill", Hanover County, Virginia], much family news, 15 December 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
      - H[attie] L. P[owell], Blenheim, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to "sister" [Rebecca Powell], n.p., 16 December 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Refers to travel by carriage; discusses mailing "bleached cotton"; family news.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to wife [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 17 December [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)